What to Expect: First Steps
The first step of your radiation
journey is a consultation
with your radiation oncologist,
which is likely what you underwent
before watching this video.
The consultation is an appointment
in which you speak to your radiation
oncologist
about your medical and cancer history,
and let us know how you are feeling.
Your radiation oncologist
may go over your imaging or pathology
results with you, then discuss
their recommendations for next steps.
Sometimes these recommendations require
input from a multidisciplinary
panel of other oncologists,
such as medical oncologist,
surgical oncologist,
pathologists, and radiologists.
If that is the case, your story will be
brought to this multidisciplinary panel
called a Tumor Board
that meets once a week.
The experts will weigh in
on various aspects of your care,
and a consensus will be reached on
what to do next.
Your doctor will
then share this plan with you.
The plan may have various aspects
such as timing and the order of radiation,
systemic treatment or surgery.
If the plan is to proceed with radiation
treatment, your radiation oncologist
will discuss with you
what this radiation plan entails.
The side effects and what to do next.
You can, of course, ask questions
and discuss options as available.